SARAH CONWAY

Senior software engineer, frontend web developer, senior website manager, technical support engineer, developer advocate, conference organizer, diversity committee chair, program organizer, social media manager, and copy editor are some of the hats I've worn in 11+ years of professional experience working solo and with hybrid/remote, distributed, & global teams. I've been recognized as one of the 2022 Redgate 100 Most Influential in the Database Community under "Open Source Heroes" & "Open Source Database", and am also a #PostgresFriend. Catch me on LinkedIn Learning creating introductory courses for PostgreSQL.

EXPERIENCE

EDB, Remote - Cloud Evangelist

MARCH 2022 - PRESENT

I'm both a **Cloud Evangelist** on the **CTO Team** at EDB and **Cloud Solutions Architect** on the **Cloud Sales & Marketing team** for EDB's BigAnimal, a fully managed Database as a Service solution for running PostgreSQL clusters in the cloud.

I'm helping to lead Postgres evangelism within EDB's senior leadership team through:

- Thought leadership
- PostgreSQL community leadership and involvement
- Content creation (blog posts, webinars, training programs, videos)
- Speaking at conferences & webinars
- Competitive analysis and positioning
- Technology research and innovation
- Benchmarking costs and performance
- Measuring and analyzing value of EDB solutions

And am also focused on building customer relationships through strategic interaction:

- Helping customers understand the value proposition
- Assisting key customers with strategic projects
- Understanding customer needs and shaping account strategy
- Designing and developing proof of concept features, tools, and products
- Providing best practices and advice
- Leading & participating in workshops and trainings

LinkedIn Learning, Remote - LinkedIn Learning Instructor

SEPTEMBER 2022 - PRESENT

- Introduction to ETL and ELT in PostgreSQL <u>Created a complete course</u>.
- Introduction to PostgreSQL Course in progress.
- PostgreSQL Code Challenges Course in progress.

Crunchy Data, Remote - Senior Software Engineer

MARCH 2017 - MARCH 2022

- Senior Frontend Developer Full project ownership and collaboration on distributed/remote teams for multiple frontend applications and websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Reactstrap, React JS, TypeScript, Hugo, and a variety of other frontend technologies.
- Senior Software Engineer Developed the <u>Crunchy Data PostgreSOL</u>
 <u>Operator</u> and <u>Crunchy Data Container Suite</u>, containerization technology that provides a high-level abstraction and solution for rapid creation and simplified management of PostgreSQL clusters, using Kubernetes, OpenShift, Docker, Go, JSON, & SQL. Wrote public-facing documentation for both.
- Technical Support Engineer Participated in a 24x7 support rotation providing real-time customer support to users from all technical backgrounds, from sales experts to database administrators, using OSTicket. Support was provided for high availability PostgreSQL in on-premise, public & private cloud, and container environments. Wrote technical support guides for internal teams & customers.

Able to work:

24 hrs/day, 7 days/week

Located in:

Southern California (Remote Only)

sarah.beth.conway@gmail.com

https://sarahinsandiego.github.io
/portfolio/

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Git/GitHub, HTML, CSS3, SCSS, SASS, JavaScript, jQuery, React JS, Alpine JS, Slides JS, Bootstrap, Reactstrap, Tailwind, ES6, Rest APIs, TypeScript, Python, Go, PHP, Bash, Shell, JSON, Linux, Unix, Windows, HubSpot, Hugo, Drupal, Express, Heroku, Apache, Django, Node.js, Webpack, NPM, Yarn, Jest, Cypress, PostgreSQL, Azure, Kubernetes, OpenShift, Docker, Vagrant, Virtualization, Katacoda, Google Cloud Platform, AWS, Patternfly, ChartJS, OpenLayers, Google Charts, ESLint, Prettier, LaTeX, Pandoc, ASCII, Markdown, Wiki, SEO, Google Ad Words, Google Tag Manager, Google Analytics, OSTicket, High Availability, Scalability, Accessibility, Performance, Responsiveness, Automation, CI/CD, Version Control, Single Page Applications (SPAs), User Experience (UX) and Design, User Interfaces (UI), ETL, JAMStack, Microsoft Power Automate, Grafana, Prometheus

RELATIONAL SKILLS

Startup (Fast-Paced) Environments, Digital Marketing, Social Media Management, Customer Service, Community Engagement & Success, Project Owner/Management, Product Lifecycle, Leadership, Training, Content Management, Content Editing, Content Writing, Mentorship, Code Review, Webinars, Presentations, Information Architecture, Documentation, Developer Evangelism & Advocacy, Agile, Scrum, Linear, Slack, Notion, Jira, Kanban, G Suite, Microsoft 365, Figma

PostgreSQL US, Remote - Community Leader

JANUARY 2012 - JULY 2022

- Board Director [May 2022 Present]
- PostgreSQL US Diversity Committee Chair [Oct 2019 Present] Program Organizer for Google Code-in 2018 & Google Season of Docs 2019, Scholarship Administrator, Code Mentor, Social Media Manager, Copy Editor, Documentation Writer, Code Reviewer
- PostgreSQL Community Website Website Developer Completed a refactor of the primary PostgreSQL, Python, Git, & Django.
- Frontend Website Developer [Jan 2012 Jan 2020] Sole project owner and website manager for a number of community conference websites, including but not limited to Page-00, Page-00, PostgresOpen 2018, PostgresOpen 2019, and many others.
- PostgresOpen Conference Organizer [Jan 2016 Jan 2020] Website Manager, Social Media Manager, Presenter, Developer Advocate, Copy Editor, Marketer, Outreach Strategist

CONTENT CREATION

EDB

- Presented: Discussing Kubernetes Operators for PostgreSQL (PostgresVision)
- Presented: PostgreSQL What's it all about? (PgCMH)
- Published: The Importance of Giving Back: Analyzing Code Contributions to PostgreSOL 15
- Published: PostgreSOL: Powered by Community and Open Source
- Published: The True Costs of Moving to the Cloud
- Published: PostgreSQL Performance Improvements Part 2: Why you need the latest PostgreSQL
- Published: EDB BigAnimal: The Complete PostgreSOL-as-a-Service Experience

Crunchy Data

- Presented: Containerizing PostgreSQL for Cloud Natives Video
- Presented: Don't Panic: Use the PostgreSQL Operator for Kubernetes and OpenShift Video Slides
- Presented: A Kubernetes Operator for PostgreSQL <u>Video</u> <u>Slides</u>
- Published: pgBackRest Performing Backups on a Standby Cluster

Individual

- Presented: Securing Your Database in Amazon RDS <u>Video</u> <u>Slides</u>
- Presented: The Three Musketeers Authentication, Authorization, and Accounting <u>Video</u> <u>Slides</u>

FRONT FND PORTFOLIO

Additional screenshots and a list of websites I've contributed to or fully developed can be found on my <u>LinkedIn</u>; those found here are isolated examples of my most recent work. All screenshots are partial images of longer pages.

Crunchy Data

https://imgur.com/a/2vkPUEU

Postgres Open

• https://imgur.com/a/ejgjExY

United States PostgreSQL Association (PgUS)

https://imgur.com/a/diIZTOC

EDUCATION

Western Governors University, Remote - Bachelor's Degree - Information Technology / Cyber & Computer Forensics and Counterterrorism

JULY 2017 - DECEMBER 2019

Cuyamaca College, San Diego, CA - Associate's Degree - Network Administration

JULY 2011 - JUNE 2015

Cuyamaca College, San Diego, CA - Associate's Degree - Telecommunications

JULY 2011 - JUNE 2015

CERTIFICATES

Professional Certificates & Licenses:

- HIPAA Exams HIPAA Business Associate Certification
- EC-Council Certified Encryption Specialist
- CIWcertified Web Security Associate
- ISC2 Systems Security Certified Practitioner
- Cuyamaca College Computer Support Technician
- Cuyamaca College Telecommunications Networking Technician
- Cuyamaca College Computer Network Administration
- CompTIA Project+ (Expired Jul 2021)
- CompTIA Network+ (Expired Nov 2020)
- CompTIA Security+ (Expired Oct 2020)
- CompTIA A+ (Expired Aug 2020)